[Music]
Bonswar Roxan. Hi Roxen. How are you
doing? Hi Bab. Bon. Good. And you?
Amazing. Yeah, very very good. Um, yeah,
as I mentioned, we wanted to make sure
that we keep the community engaged till
the end. So, uh, we put you there not
because you're not important, but
because you're the important piece, uh,
to make this a perfect rap. So, really
excited to hear about I mean, if you've
been Sorry. Wow, it's getting late,
guys. This is it. Um, yeah.
So yeah, if you've been living under a
rock then uh oran is going to share with
you what inshift is but if not uh she'll
explain what inf is doing in the context
of infra and yeah I think uh this is it
uh the floor is yours Roxan. Thank you
so much. Thanks. So yeah, uh nice to
meet you everyone. Um I'm Oxen, CEO and
co-founder of any shift. Um we are
building a AI DevOps agent that can
actually take a GitHub issue and create
a pull request out of it. And today I
will speak about the importance of
context um for AI application when it
comes to your infrastructure.
This is a subject we are dealing with uh
dayto-day at any shift and why context
is so important and spoiler alert uh
your infrastructure is a graph and so
you should uh see it as
is. So I'm just going to begin uh with a
small um introduction about um how I'm
going to speak about infrastructure and
uh AI context. Like the first part of
this like presentation is to explain
like why it's so important and for like
infrastructure as code uh generation um
especially and why very often it fails
short when you use um copilot cursor to
actually generate your infrastructure as
code code. Then a small live demo uh to
show why in practice it doesn't work. Uh
and the last part would be like how to
actually like um create uh those graph
in practice. Um how to actually like uh
get some remediation uh to the this
shortcom of generating the right
infrastructure as code uh relative to
your infrastructure.
So the first part uh I'm want to speak
about would be kind of a concrete
example on why uh infrastructure as code
generation uh still doesn't work that
well um when you use it in your favorite
tools uh you can use github compilot
cursor etc and very often it's good like
it creates something that makes sense
but it would be like snipets of code but
it's never like wow Oh, it's often ma
why not? And uh here I want to explain
why. So to do so um I took a simple
instruction um to actually uh do like
kind of day-to-day task for like an SV
um such as like uh please create like an
AWS or like a VPC connection in
terapform. The first person I would ask
uh this task to would be a dev a
developer.
uh here would be like an example of the
code uh that uh should have been created
could have been created uh with my VPC
ping connection. So here you can see my
two VPCs with outcoded values like very
often and I don't know like for those of
of you that have large code bases but
you will have like art values
um and like um also like clickups
resources in your cloud uh because it's
never perfect and your developer um very
potentially doesn't know like the good
practices obviously it's not good to
have outcode values in your code but did
some things that worked and moved to
something
else. The right thing that he should
have done would be to actually like
create uh some dynamic dependencies uh
to avoid a booking change in the future.
So here this is what I as the same thing
to GitHub copilot and GitHub copilot is
slightly more aware of the good
practices on my def and has created uh
the right uh dependencies so like
dynamic dependencies not static ones
um you can see it here um the thing is
um is that GitHub copilot doesn't know
where to fetch my main VPC for this VPC
connection So what it's going to try to
do is to continue code generation as
like a good LLM would do. Uh and here is
generating a new VPC
um which would work in practice but
which is not realistic. I want my main
VPC uh to be referred
to and this is a thing with LMS. uh they
don't have like the entire context of
your infrastructure and so they're
missing those dependencies that are
needed to actually like make the right
fences. So the question that I guess a
lot of like a lot of you would have
would be like okay so could cursor do it
uh because cursor um is actually a
perfect tool to make uh those mapping
between different code
files. Um this example here is uh to
highlight uh what I expected. Uh I
actually wanted to have like uh a data
source referring so right here referring
to my main VPC which was already defined
and running in like defined in another
repository. This is the actual codes
that um someone like in my S team DevOps
team would have
done. Um but let's go back to my
previous example with my developer who
has artcoded uh some values. Um we all
have some like um not the best practices
in our code but like you will have some
as good values
um intricated modules and also like live
resources that are living with no
definition uh within um within your code
just define clickups in your cloud
console and because of that when I'm
actually trying to make this ping
connect VBC connection with the right
data source here what you can see is
that a tool such as cursor is strictly
incapable of making uh this reference
this connection. Why? Uh it's because uh
those ids um actually only ids defined
in the cloud live cloud data and that
cursor doesn't have any ID of it just
has the code uh in mind. So you cannot
do the connection between this ID and
this VPC and to make this connection a
cursor or like any other like AI agents
we need to have like full cloud access
um to all the different accounts etc and
to the ids and ends of the
resources. So I just want to put uh like
to highlight it in a small demo. Uh
spoiler alert uh I'm going to show a
little bit of any shifts because we are
building uh this AI context for your
infrastructure. Um and now it's going to
be fun because uh live demo part is
always the funniest part.
Um so um the example I want to to take
is actually a pretty simple example but
just to show like the limitation that
you can have depending of the tools you
use. Uh any shift we are building some
AI devops agent uh that can answer like
to question about your clouds between
different sources that you can see here
GitHub AWS data dog etc. And here so I
want to ask um do I have unsecure
um IM users insecure sorry for my
English I am
users and it's going to begin the
thinking and now I'm going to do it as
well in cursor and I need to do a small
change of
screen share
screen share my entire screen sorry for
the infinite loop And normally you
should see
it. And now I'm gonna ask to cursor as
well list um uh do I have sorry do I
have I am users that are
insecure. And um what you can see here
is that cursor um is actually going to
query uh my infrastructure as code uh
code bases. Uh you can see to the left I
have like my TF AWS
um the one for Cloudflare the repository
for Cloudflare. Um and it's going to
query like for my all my repositories
and search uh for the different IM
users. Uh actually here it's having some
hallucination and searching the web. Uh
and that's the fun part about live demo.
Uh but so let's see if I stop it and I
can actually show you a previous chat
history that I made.
Perfect. So when it didn't elucinate um
what it found in my different like uh
files. So here in my IM user files be
like to read the different users any
phone like S Jordan and Wen Fisher
uh having uh some obvious uh security uh
issues and admin access. I also have
like my animo uh user who doesn't have
like all the security checks
um and some insecure uh temp goof
user and t from goof everything is right
here and this is from the code now let's
go back to any shift and to
any so I'm going to share oh actually it
was actually working but sharing my
screen on any
shift which is this one. Sorry for the
little interruption but so uh do I have
um insecure IM
users?
Um any shift or Annie uh is answering as
well that I have Stephan Jordan and
Fisher and Anno uh that are not uh
correctly uh configured. And here you
can see that you would also get the
links uh to my AWS console because any
uh doesn't only have like the um context
of the code but also the context of the
cloud. But what I want to show here is
that more
importantly what I found here is that I
have like a temporary goof user that
cursor didn't find um that has some
accesses but which is not defined into
the
code. And here you can see my temporary
goof user with administrator access
which is obviously uh the wrong
practice.
Um and because cursor didn't have like
the cloud context, it couldn't have
found this temporary goof user which was
obviously a security issue but then
couldn't be capable of actually from
that make a remediation a pull request
to actually like uh either like create
the right um infrastructure like code to
define this goof user which is only
living in the cloud for now but also
like to change the
accesses. That's a very small example to
see how the context that's going to feed
your AI is going to be like a game
changer for the generation that you're
going to make out of it.
And so now uh when we come to the third
part which which is how we actually like
create this context I want to put a
strong emphasis about the fact that your
infrastructure is a graph
um and it's kind of um simple uh when
you see it like that um your
infrastructure is made of different
resources an EC2 instance linked to an
IM user within a VPC uh connected with
different edges and so You can see it
easily as a graph with like the
resources which are nodes and the
connection which are
edges. This graph is actually super
complex when you need to map your entire
infrastructure. It's a huge monster with
multiple accounts very often multiple
clouds t of thousands of resources and
not even speaking about all the
microservices running within. So it's
actually more looking like that uh like
it's actually a subset of your graph
infrastructure but
still and the thing is to tweet uh to
create such a graph um the two most
important parts when you need to create
like for code generation is first to
define meaningful uh edge oh sorry it's
actually a table um edge um labels um
it's not the same connection when you
connect a VPC with some net uh or a VPC
with uh some kind of the metadata uh
that you add within or the connection uh
with an S2 instance uh some edges would
be like this would be configured by this
one would be linked with so it's not
exactly the same properties that
actually make and define your
infrastructure.
Uh the second part which is super
important for code generation is m is
making this deterministic mapping
between your cloud resources and your
infrastructure as code code to be
capable of um mapping the right uh
resources to the code definition as we
have seen
before. Um I just want to finish uh this
with how to build such graph for such
context uh with two main areas uh with
the pros and cons. Um the first one is
about uh building uh a graph DB graph DB
uh which is what we do at any shift. Uh
we build and maintain this deep
knowledge graph of the infrastructure
that we then query uh for code
generation and incident remedation. Um
it's great because like you have your
entire graph in context with all the
dependencies with super high quality
data uh but uh hard to do it uh like
within a team internally because it's
super like takes a lot of time to
maintain. Uh a second power of areas of
uh not research but development uh that
is a great tool already is to use MCB
servers uh to actually fetch it live
context within your code. So for
instance, if you use like an AWS MTB
server, um you can already have a subp
parts of your live uh cloud
resources, which is great uh to have
some infos that you wouldn't have with
cursor or the code
itself. It's easier to build inhouse,
but you will still have a fragmented
view of your infrastructure. you cannot
understand all the relationship and it
cannot scale indefinitely because you
will get some weight limits when you do
too many API calls with your MCP
server. And just as a conclusion
um really want to emphasis on the
importance of context context is king.
garbage in garbage out. When it comes to
infrastructure or any other fields,
ulm to create the right uh code need to
have the right context and because your
infrastructure is a graph, it should be
uh created as
is. And that's it for me. Um I think
it's really important and I really thank
the AI native defcon for making such a
great event. um any shift and tel and
all like all the other like kind of
partners in this um fields are for me
like building end to end this context
like this AI for the future which I
believe is really like awesome.
Well, um, thank you so much, Han. Uh,
like, uh, really, really insightful talk
and, yeah, I think it'll be really
interesting to see how like some of the
blockers that you mentioned with MCP
like how that evolve within the infra
space and what any shift will do uh, in
the ecosystem. So, um, yeah, extremely
insightful. Thank you so much and thank
you to the entire community for, you
know, I I just saw in comments some
people are coming from Hawaii, from
Singapore. It's just like a a a very
very cool uh uh group of people. So,
just wanted to uh say that we appreciate
you uh for for for being